(One Step Closer)
Nice to see you all.
(Nice to see you all.)
It's been a while, Joy.
- Yes, it's been so long. - It's been a while.
I watched the preview of the show last week.
- You went to meet Ito Junji. - Right.
(Exploding with anticipation)
- You went on a trip. - He's the master artist.
Actually, people around my age...
love Ito Junji and his works.
We grew up reading "Uzumaki," "Tomie,"
and other series of his.
I wanted to style myself like Tomie back in the day.
- She had such fair skin. - Right, there's a resemblance.
- Really? - There's a resemblance.
Whenever I get bangs,
I want to style myself like her no matter what.
You know what?
- I can't picture it. - Okay.
- I've never seen him. - Right.
- The artist? - Yes, the artist.
The fact that...
- he agreed to see me... - Right. Picturing that...
- I don't know what to say. - It doesn't feel real.
Picture a major national holiday like Lunar New Year.
So you're doing the New Year's bow, and there's Beckham sitting there.
- It's... - It feels that unrealistic?
It does.
That's how it feels to me.
(Longtime Admiration)
"Longtime Admiration."
(Kian84 walks through the big crowd.)
(Reading tensely)
"Where am I?"
I'm in Japan.
I came to Tokyo.
Personally, I have huge respect for him.
His name is Ito Junji.
Kangnam said he would help me meet the artist,
and set up a meeting.
Then he really managed to get me a meeting with him.
- He said he'd get me a meeting. - That's amazing.
(He came to meet the man he's admired for a long time.)
So I'm here.
(The artist made a debut in 1987 with "Tomie.")
(His unique styles and plots...)
That's from "Uzumaki."
("Ito Junji Wins the Eisner Award for Best Edition")
("Ito Junji, the Master of Horror, Wins 2 Eisner Awards")
("Ito Junji's Work Gains Worldwide Recognition")
("He was inducted into the Will Eisner Awards Hall of Fame")
(It's equivalent to the Academy Awards.)
(The master artist of horror manga, Ito Junji)
As a little kid, I used to read a lot of comic books.
There were many series...
such as "Dragon Ball," Slam Dunk," and "One Piece."
Personally,
I loved Ito Junji's manga series...
because his story development was so original.
The basic format of comics went like this.
Once the main character beat an opponent,
a strong opponent showed up next.
The story focused on highlighting the growth of the character.
But in Ito Junji's series,
the plots were developed...
and were interpreted in a completely different way.
So I can't simply call them horror mango.
- Right. - I wouldn't even call it horror.
I had never seen anything like that before.
- He created his own genre. - I agree.
Ito Junji is his own genre.
- Right. - Yes.
No one can compare.
His manga series influenced me as an artist too.
As a kid, I enjoyed reading his manga series.
Even after I became a webtoon artist,
I kept following his career.
I like Ito Junji.
(He expressed his admiration of the artist to Kangnam.)
(I'll help you meet him.)
I just have to finish this.
- He made a call right away? - What?
(Are you making a call?)
(Is this Ito Junji's agency?)
- Kangnam... - What?
(Nervous)
(Do you mean Ito Junji, not Inagawa Junji?)
(Who's this guy? I don't know who he is.)
(Manga artist: Ito Junji, Horror storyteller: Inagawa Junji)
When you turn on the TV at night during summertime in Japan,
he's always on TV.
I guess he's a famous guy.
(Let's get you a meeting with the manga artist.)
(I'll talk to him for you.)
When he said he'd help me meet him,
- I was skeptical. - You didn't make much of it.
I'm a huge fan.
So I try to follow him online.
- But he rarely posts things online. - Right.
That's why...
if I'm being honest,
I never imagined I would be able to meet him.
Well, we move in completely different circles.
I never thought I would be able to meet him.
I was still skeptical even during the interview.
- Even after arriving in Japan? - Yes.
- Kangnam loves pranking people. - Right.
He might introduce his friend named Junji.
("This is my friend, Junji, not Ito Junji.")
Seriously.
- I would've gotten physical then. - "This is my friend, Ito Junji."
- Right. That must be a common name. - Of course.
It's a common name.
(He flew to Japan to meet the manga artist.)
- You went there only with a bag? - Yes.
"Hamamatsucho Station."
I guess you're taking the subway.
Yes. Taxis in Japan are expensive.
Insert cash or a credit card.
(He follows the voice guidance to buy the ticket.)
The ticket machines offer Korean translation these days.
Right.
Will this get me to my destination?
- My gosh. - What?
What? Oh, are you Korean?
- Ma'am. - Yes.
- What? - There's this monorail.
- Can I get on it with this? - There's a Korean worker.
You can take the next one. It's express, so it's quicker.
- I see. - Scan it.
- Scan it when you get off too. - Okay.
- Thank you. - Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year. - Thanks.
I wanted to use some Japanese phrases I learned.
It's like I'm at Seoul Station.
There are many subway trains.
(He gets on the train while mumbling Japanese to himself.)
You must start to feel nervous on the train.
(Heading downtown with excitement and nervousness)
- I just noticed your sweatshirt... - Right.
- is Ito Junji's merchandise. Right? - Right.
("Souichi's Diary of Curses")
My gosh, cherry blossoms are already in bloom.
Already?
(The flowers are in full bloom like his heart.)
The flowers have bloomed.
(Japan and my heart are in spring.)
It feels like I'm dreaming.
It's so romantic right now.
It's like a scene from a Japanese movie.
(Ito Junji...)
(and Kian84)
(Now...)
He's on his way now.
I look pretty cool in this clip.
What a surprise choice of music for Kian84.
Personally, I have huge respect for him.
He's a manga artist.
It feels like I'm dreaming right now.
I bet. It must feel so surreal.
Is this the place?
"Log."
(He goes straight to a building without any hesitation.)
- What? - What?
This is the place.
- You're meeting him there? - No, I won't go to his house.
He wouldn't just barge into someone's home.
And bang on his door?
"Junji!"
"Junji."
(What?)
That would be random.
That's my lodging.
- I need to get ready first. - Of course.
I'm meeting him the next day. This is only my first day.
I can't pound on his door as soon as I get there.
- I can picture you doing that. - Gosh, no.
I'm more socially adapted now.
This is the place.
(He checks in first like a well-mannered man.)
I see. This is the place.
(He booked a house in advance.)
This is nice.
- He found a cute and cozy place. - Yes.
I see tatami too.
(The 2nd-floor bedroom is covered with tatami.)
Hotels look the same. You know?
Even the layout and service are similar.
I wanted to get the local vibe, so I rented a house instead.
The units on the platform were spacious and cheap.
- It's a great platform. - Right.
They're better than hotels.
What's this? It's the bathroom.
(He checks the bathroom first.)
Gosh, look at all these stairs.
- That's a typical house in Japan. - Stairs...
I see.
(Drawing open the curtains first)
(Let me open up the windows too.)
It looks like a house you'd see in Japanese movies.
(Sitting down)
(He organizes his belongings as soon as he sits down.)
It's wrinkled. Darn it.
- Oh, my. - You packed a button-down shirt.
You had a button-down shirt in the bag? Oh, my.
What's that? Things keep on coming out of that bag.
- Where did he get the jacket? - I was so surprised.
How did you pull out a suit from that bag?
You can stay in my bag if you want.
Everything can fit in the bag.
Hey, it's not wrinkled at all.
(He carefully brought a suit and a tie.)
I only wear suits once a year for the year-end awards ceremony.
I don't even wear a suit to weddings.
I rarely wear suits.
That was a long time ago.
What's wrong with my face?
(Gosh, come on.)
Did I get stung by a bee?
You looked so chubby then.
That was ten years ago.
- Ten years ago? - Yes.
I'm finally meeting the artist I've wanted to meet most.
I didn't think it was polite of me...
to show up in a casual outfit.
I wanted to look neat for him.
Right.
(I brought a suit to look neat.)
(He finishes putting away his things after hanging up the suit.)
(Staring out the window)
(I can't believe I'm here in Japan to meet him.)
(He feels the relaxed vibe of Tokyo through the window.)
- What a nice atmosphere. - Right.
(Slurping)
(He fills his stomach with cup noodles.)
(Munching)
(Drinking up the broth too)
I'm stuffed.
(He grabs a quick meal with cup noodles.)
(He grabs a box and climbs the stairs.)
Gosh, it's cold.
(Plopping down)
(Staring)
Questions for him...
(Hello. It's nice to meet you.)
I studied a bit.
(A long list of questions)
"It feels like a dream to meet you."
"It feels like..."
(It feels like a dream.)
"It feels like a dream."
I grew up reading your comics.
So I became a manga artist.
Later on, you had a huge influence on me.
I was informed...
about three months ago that I'd be able to meet him.
I've been studying Japanese quite diligently...
after hearing the news.
I spent as much time studying Japanese as running...
- because... - You studied that much?
he put aside time for our meeting.
I didn't want to look silly...
and make mistakes while speaking in Japanese.
I wrote down a lot of things I wanted to tell him.
I practiced a lot too.
If I studied this hard when I was young...
Well, I still wouldn't have been able to get into SNU.
Anyway, the point is...
I studied a lot and became to enjoy it.
So I kept studying it.
"I think it was around 1994."
"I saw your manga series in an old bookstore..."
"For the first time."
(He looks up the words he doesn't know.)
(Unlike 6 months ago...)
(when he could only list simple words in Japanese,)
"I saw it for the first time."
(it's quite an improvement.)
He's serious about learning Japanese.
He was studying in his waiting room too.
(Impressed)
It all started with you.
I always saw you studying in your spare time.
"How are things with you these days?"
(He keeps practicing the questions.)
"Out of all your manga characters,"
"my favorite one is Souichi."
This character right here is my favorite character.
His name is Souichi.
He's always low on iron, so he always has nails in his mouth.
He's low on iron?
He's quite twisted too.
He reminds me of myself when I was young.
I'm getting the feeling that he might have been...
like Souichi when he was young too.
How old is he?
He was born in 1963. So he's 21 years older than me.
- He's the same age as my mother. - He's about the same age as my mom.
- Really? - He's 64 years old?
(He's 64 years old?)
I should ask him about his health then.
"Your health." That's the word.
(He adds more questions out of sincerity.)
"How is your cat doing?"
"What kind of student were you in school?"
"Do you still draw?"
"Lastly,"
"how do you want the world to remember you?"
(Getting sentimental)
That reminds me of something. My fans from abroad...
always study Korean...
- Right. - and practice the sentences,
so they can speak Korean to me.
- That's touching. - I can picture my fans...
- Right. - studying like him.
- This is such a touching moment. - Same here. This is so touching.
Both of your fans from Japan practice Korean...
- out of love for you guys. - Right.
- Right. They practice Korean. - They study Korean for you.
- Right. - I never thought...
- I'd be anyone's fan. But I was. - Exactly.
- You're his fan. - Right. After all these years.
It's rare to feel those emotions after getting old.
Right. I don't think I had that experience.
If I need more help, I'll try to be more flexible when I meet him.
(Ripping open)
(Why is he suddenly opening up a box?)
What?
(Reaching)
You got a canvas.
- You're going to paint there? - Yes.
(He gently tosses the canvas on the floor.)
(He fills the ramyeon cup with water and comes upstairs.)
Oh, my.
(He grabs the tablet PC.)
(Let's see.)
Ito Junji.
(He looks up pictures of Ito Junji online.)
I see. You'll paint him a portrait?
I grew up reading...
Ito Junji's manga series.
That inspired me to draw later in my life.
I thought giving him a painting as a gift would be a nice gesture.
- He must feel so proud. - So I painted.
Health.
(What should I paint?)
It's the Year of the Horse.
(A painting for good health or the Year of the Horse?)
It must've been so hard to decide.
- It was going to be a present. - Right.
I was planning to give it to a manga artist I admired.
So I had a hard time deciding.
And giving a painting to a well-respected artist isn't easy.
(Let me start painting.)
(He grabs the paint after thinking for a while.)
(He puts a blob of paint on the canvas.)
(He calmly starts painting.)
(He highlights his unique painting style.)
(Then he sighs.)
(Just as he gets into it, he suddenly stops.)
You have a lot on your mind, right?
- Yes, I had a lot on my mind. - Right.
It's tough when you have a lot on your mind.
Painting for...
a manga artist I admire is not easy.
(He puts down the paintbrush...)
(and grabs the paint tube again.)
(He starts covering it up with the brush without hesitation.)
- There's no hesitation. - Why are you doing that?
- Covering up? - You just covered up...
- the sketch with the paint? - Right.
He didn't like it.
(He covers it up completely.)
It was...
I mean, other fans must've given him their artworks as presents.
I didn't want mine to look similar to theirs.
I worked especially hard on the painting.
(The painting goes back to square one just like that.)
(Great. Let me start over.)
(Ripping)
(He squeezes paint onto the torn cardboard.)
(Focused)
(He starts painting after thinking for a while.)
I wonder what he's going to paint.
(Smiling)
I've given away a lot of my paintings as presents.
But the painting I did for him...
was the most meaningful one.
I worked really hard on the painting.
He showed me how amazing manga artists could be...
and how cool it was to have this career.
He inspired me to see that.
(Kian84 slowly gets into it.)
Do I have hand tremors? Why are they shaking so much?
(He saw countless pictures of his idol.)
Gosh, I'm...
Oh, my back.
(He endures the back pain due to the uncomfortable posture...)
(and focuses on the painting again.)
(Like Tokyo's deep-blue night,)
(his painting gradually darkens.)
(He doesn't lose focusing until the end and forgets the back pain.)
(He signs his name in the corner of the canvas.)
- I got goosebumps. - He's going to love it.
Ito Junji reminds me of space.
So I went with the shades of blue to represent space.
I added swirling patterns on the side.
He draws people in.
His work...
kind of reminds me of space.
He pulls people in like a black hole.
That's who he is to me.
You compared him to space. That's just...
I'm done.
Oh, my back.
My goodness, my back.
(He finally stretches his back after finishing the painting.)
I'm so tired.
Oh, my. My back hurts.
(In no time, the night deepens like space.)
(Impressed)
- I just got goosebumps. - You did an amazing job.
- Right. - I thought it was a picture.
Right.
We all know how talented you are.
But because you put your heart into it,
it looks exceptional.
I painted a younger version of him.
- Look at the swirling patterns. - Gosh.
How many hours did it take?
About two and a half hours.
That took a lot of time.
When you did my portrait, you finished in an instant, right?
I didn't try so hard on that one.
He made me look like the root of a radish.
My yard still scares me from time to time.
(His half-hearted paintings are mentioned one after another.)
(The next day after a long day of painting)
(He's going to meet Ito Junji today!)
Gosh, it's cold.
- It was so cold in Japan. - Right, it's cold there.
You need to have layers of blankets too.
I guess you didn't pack pajamas in your bag.
(Embarrassed)
(He wakes up while trembling in cold without pajamas.)
(Sniffling)
It's 9am.
Gosh, I should get ready.
- What? They're the same pants. - You're wearing dress pants?
They're dress pants.
(What is that?)
- What? - I only brought one bag.
I would have brought a suitcase if I packed extra pants.
You must have ironed them before packing, right?
- I didn't. - You didn't?
I washed them after wearing them for a full week.
- Well, pants... - So you just assume wearing them...
- will get rid of the wrinkles? - Yes, that gets rid of wrinkles.
Right. Spray some water, and the wrinkles are gone.
(He's wearing the dress pants he ironed last night.)
- He wore them to sleep. - That's crazy.
(Warming up his naked upper body)
(Picking up)
(He heads downstairs with food containers.)
Why do you have food containers?
- You had them in the bag? - Yes.
But you didn't pack pajamas.
(Food containers are more important than pajamas.)
I can't survive winter in Japan. It's way too cold.
(He comes down to the kitchen with the containers.)
The boxed meal...
- A boxed meal? - You'll pack a boxed meal?
- He's going to pack a boxed meal. - Did you...
(Opening up)
(Let me see.)
(He takes out all kinds of ingredients from the fridge.)
Just don't make fried rice.
It's fried rice.
(That's correct!)
(Oh, dear me!)
I'm suddenly getting so worried.
You've had it, right?
Right. His kimchi fried rice was unforgettable.
(Kian84 brought kimchi fried rice on the field day.)
(The flavor of the fried rice hit him pretty hard.)
I can still taste the oil in my mouth.
You changed the recipe, right?
- You changed it, right? - I did.
I improved it about three steps from the old recipe.
- What a relief. - Three steps?
He should've improved it more.
(He takes out various ingredients from the fridge.)
(Placing them down)
He's going to a boxed meal with other boxed meals.
Well, Ito Junji...
can probably afford to eat whatever he wants.
So cooking was probably the best thing I could do.
He can't buy my food at markets or restaurants.
That's why I decided to cook.
I bought some ingredients...
to make kimchi fried rice which is my best dish.
(He bought the ingredients the night before.)
(Meat)
(Kimchi)
(Eggs)
(Stir-Fry84 carefully picks up the ingredients.)
Why do you keep looking for oil?
No.
My fried rice never fails.
I've never failed with this dish. It always comes out tasty.
I can't make it look nice.
But when it comes to flavors, no other fried rice can beat mine.
I am very good at...
making the flavorful taste of fried rice.
(He will serve his flavorful kimchi fried rice to his idol.)
(He washes his hands first before cooking.)
(Let me show off my culinary skills.)
(He grabs the meat first.)
(He removes the wrapper.)
(Tossing it into the frying pan)
This is pretty high heat.
(The meat smoke fills up the kitchen.)
(Flipping)
(It's almost cooked. So let me lower the heat.)
(Beeping)
(Adding rice)
- Rice. - Rice.
(Adding kimchi too)
(As this is his specialty, he confidently cooks it.)
Today, you're following the steps.
That already looks so tasty.
(Stir-fry the meat, kimchi, and rice thoroughly.)
When it comes to kimchi fried rice,
you need a good balance of sour, sweet, and salty flavors.
With Korean kimchi, I have to add sugar.
Korean kimchi doesn't taste sweet.
So I must add sugar to it.
But the kimchi bought in Japan is typically sweet.
I think it already has a lot of sugar in it.
I got the sour and sweet flavors from the kimchi.
Then I added a bit of saltiness too.
I stir-fried the rice with all three flavors.
You have your own philosophy now.
- Of course. - Right.
- You can explain your dish well. - Right.
I sound like an expert, right?
(Feeling proud)
(The fried-rice philosopher puts his heart into it.)
- The color is starting to show. - My color is showing, right?
- It's getting darker. - Right. It's the color...
- of your kimchi fried rice. - Yes. That's right.
I didn't think he could recreate that in Japan.
Don't you want to have another field day after watching that?
(Shocked)
(I'll make it anytime you want.)
This looks good enough.
(It's stir-fried nicely.)
(Transferring the food to the container)
You didn't even taste it to see how it was.
I don't check the seasoning.
But you weren't cooking for yourself.
What? But still. I had faith in my cooking skills.
I was confident.
It looks pretty good.
Dae Ho, this is how you pack a boxed meal.
(Unbelievable)
The only difference is the container.
(The only difference is the container.)
Seriously.
The meal you brought looked undesirable.
(The meal you brought looked undesirable.)
If you packed it in a plastic bag, it would've looked the same.
(The meaningless fight between Stir-Fry84 and Bibim84)
Eggs.
(I should fry up eggs too.)
(Drizzling the olive oil)
(Cracking)
(Popping out)
Oh, no.
- Oh, no. - My goodness.
(He spills the egg on the kitchen counter.)
Darn it.
What a waste of food.
No, please.
Please don't do that, Kian84.
What a waste of food.
No, please.
Please don't do that, Kian84.
(Slurping it up)
(He tries to rescue the fallen egg.)
It's going in.
(Sucking it up)
(It's successfully rescued.)
It's a waste.
- Come on. - It's a waste.
You should've sprinkled some seasoning on it.
Then it would look like I'm having a meal.
Seriously.
(Sucking it up)
(Humming)
- Good. - It'll improve your singing.
(It's tasty.)
I should spread the egg batter thin.
(He stirs the eggs thoroughly and pours them into the pan.)
(He cooks it thoroughly and evenly.)
- Will it go on top of the rice? - It will go on top of the rice.
- It's omurice. - You're pulling out all the stops.
(Adding the omelet on top of the fried rice)
(Opening up)
(He grabs two cherry tomatoes.)
- Tomatoes. - Cherry tomatoes.
My gosh.
I didn't expect to do this.
I don't even do that for my mom.
He's trying to take over the bad son title.
(Welcome to the club.)
- With some red cherry tomatoes... - It brightens the dish.
- Yes. - Yes.
- Dried lavers too? - Dried lavers.
I guess he's making something.
(He cuts a thin strip.)
(Focused)
Isn't that cute?
(Chuckling)
(I need to fix it.)
- I can't believe he's doing this. - I know, right?
You must really like him.
(Carefully decorating the boxed meal)
(Giggling)
(Making eyebrows too)
The dish is called Kimchi Fried Rice from the Dead.
Since his characters have a grotesque feel,
I tried to make it look grotesque.
I used the omelet to portray the flesh.
I gave it eyes with cherry tomatoes.
I made a smile with the dried lavers.
With this mouth, it looks like it's giggling.
That's it.
But the thing is,
he's a bit on the older side.
So I thought he needed more vegetables.
I gave it a head with the salad. The salad is the head.
It's fun to look at it before eating it.
I maximized that effect.
I should be careful carrying them. I don't want to ruin them.
- They look cute. - Perfect.
(Impressed)
- You poured your heart into it. - He gets a lot of points for that.
The one in the middle seems to be suffocating.
- It's stuck between the windows. - Right.
Right.
(This one seems to be doing okay compared to others.)
Let me wash up.
(Let me wash up.)
(He will brush his teeth and take a shower at the same time.)
Is your underwear stitched onto your pants?
(Is your underwear stitched onto your pants?)
That's...
- for reducing the dressing time. - What...
- To change in one go? - It's a useful tip.
- So you can put them on at once? - At once.
- I do that too. All in one go. - Right.
But it's fun to take them off...
- all in one go. - Right.
I thought they were trendy sagging pants.
(I thought they were trendy sagging pants.)
- Sagging dress pants. - Sagging dress pants.
(He takes off the sagging pants and takes a shower.)
Gosh, it's cold.
- What? - What?
(Screaming)
Maybe, you didn't turn...
- on the hot water. - I bet you didn't turn it on.
Right. There has to be hot water.
The house was cold.
- I thought it only had cold water. - No.
What kind of house doesn't have hot water?
It's so cold!
(Screaming)
I tried to endure the cold water as much as I could.
- What are you doing? - That's the heater.
- He's a fool. - That's the heater?
Gosh, it's cold.
In Korea, we can get hot water...
- once we turn on the boiler. - Right.
- In Japan, it's in the bathroom. - There's a button.
- Really? - It's in the bathroom.
- The water heater? - Yes, the water heater.
(Sniffling)
(I should hurry up and go meet Junji.)
- You brought a zipper tie. - Yes.
(He puts on a suit to look formal.)
I don't wear a suit unless I'm going to an awards ceremony.
(He also grabs the painting for Junji.)
(Once he packs the boxed meals, he's ready to go.)
(Sir, I'm on my way now.)
Gosh, this is making me shy.
- "Stay with me." - He...
- Look at his sock. - What?
(A flaw is exposed.)
- There's a hole. - Please meet him outdoors.
Why do you have a hole in your sock?
I got a hole only after wearing them twice.
They're so useless.
(They're so useless.)
It's sunny.
(His outfit looks perfect with shoes on.)
It came in no time.
(A taxi arrives.)
Hello.
Please put on your seat belt.
Okay.
(He sets out to meet Junji.)
(He makes sure to study Japanese.)
(I can't believe I'm going to meet Junji.)
My gosh.
(Feeling excited)
(As the car drives along with him feeling excited...)
We've arrived.
(Taxi Driver: We've arrived.)
(He arrives at the destination.)
Where is this place?
(Looking around)
Where is he?
(Curious)
(Amazed)
So this is Akihabara?
Akihabara?
Akihabara is such a fun place.
It's the mecca of anime.
(This place is called the mecca of anime.)
(Akihabara)
(The streets are filled with...)
That's so cool.
(Gacha shops)
(Anime figure stores)
(Anime pop-up events)
It's got everything.
(On top of that, there are all kinds of arcade machines...)
(and game merchandise.)
It's Halloween over there all year round.
Right.
- Oh, there? - Akihabara.
That's a fun place.
I remember the first time I went there.
Three or four hours flew by in a flash.
- Right? - Yes.
I bet they sell everything there like figurines and so on.
You'll find merchandise from your favorite series.
- Really? - Yes.
- It's got rare figurines too. - Yes.
Figurines from "Dragon Ball" and so on.
- I'd love to go there. - It's fun.
This place is crazy.
(Impressed)
I really wanted to come here when I was a kid.
Right.
Here's what I know about Akihabara.
People think of Harlem when they talk about hip-hop music.
When it comes to games, manga, and anime,
people think of Akihabara.
- That's what it's known for. - Right.
Isn't it the number one destination for it?
Everything I wanted as a kid could be found here.
So I really wanted to come here.
I had some time before meeting him.
I wanted to buy some of his art books and look around.
That's why I went there.
(That's why I came to Akihabara.)
I've been so caught up in my life that it took me this long.
It felt like I came to the starting point...
of everything I loved as a kid.
(It felt like I came to the starting point.)
(He finally walks the streets of Tokyo.)
You look like a Japanese office worker.
Seriously.
(Employee Ki is getting to work at Akihabara.)
(Stopping)
There are Mario Karts.
I've been on those before.
It was when I went on a trip with my friends.
Gosh, aren't they cold?
It's fun to see people there.
(This is really Akihabara.)
Gosh, it's amazing here.
(The street he dreamed of unfolds before his eyes.)
- I could stay there all day. - Right.
(This place is full of things to see.)
Animate.
(This time, he spots an anime merch store.)
Even in Akihabara, this place is known as...
a big and famous merch store.
Two buildings are used as a merch store.
- Two buildings? - It's an antlion pit.
(Should I take a look inside?)
(Amazed)
Gosh, there are so many things.
(It's crowded with people wanting to buy merch.)
(Let's take a look in earnest.)
Gosh, it's Totoro.
It's a Ghibli vinyl record.
(He finds a Ghibli vinyl record.)
How was this drawn so well?
(How was this drawn so well?)
It's the Gundam.
The colors of these times feel much better.
(He finds a vinyl record of "Mobile Suit Gundam III.")
The colors were used so well.
I found the usage of colors in the painting very interesting.
Was this done in pastel?
Since I paint a lot these days, paintings are all I see.
I wondered what was used.
These colors were created in pastel.
(These colors were created in pastel.)
I just say, "This looks nice."
- But he catches the details. - Since he's an artist.
Artists are different.
Do they have Ito Junji's works?
(He roams around looking for Ito Junji's works.)
Gosh! "Tomie!"
(Gosh! "Tomie!")
As expected.
- Right. - There are so many of them.
(He finally finds the section with Ito Junji's works.)
(He runs a quick scan.)
There are so many of them. "Tomie."
What?
I've never seen this one.
- I haven't seen this series. - What is that?
I haven't seen that before as well.
Is it a collection of past works?
(Heart pounding)
(Let's stay calm to choose.)
(Let's see.)
"Best of Best."
(He picks up an Ito Junji bestseller.)
I'll take these two.
(He also adds a rare work.)
Volumes 1 and 2.
I should get this as well.
He got a lot.
(He adds two more after long consideration.)
(After carrying the books carefully,)
(he moves to the counter.)
Will you use a plastic bag?
Yes!
(Peeking)
The last book was 40 dollars.
(It's around 77 dollars in total.)
He's a writer who makes Kian84 spend money.
Oh, a plastic bag? No, thanks.
It's okay!
- You said yes earlier. - You said yes earlier.
(You said yes earlier.)
I say yes whenever something long is said to me.
I didn't want to get caught with this one.
(Feeling embarrassed)
(He packs and takes the 4 books carefully...)
(and heads out.)
- I can spend a whole day there. - Right.
There's no doubt about that.
(It was a pleasant spend.)
(He preciously carries his books and continues to walk.)
It's finally time to meet him.
(Sighing)
(Placing down)
(He drops his bag as well.)
Gosh, my back.
(Kian84 sits on the street after walking for a while.)
(Dragging)
(Grabbing)
(Sniffing)
What?
Gosh, it's the smell of a new book.
I love the smell of new books.
The smell of new books with the ink.
- Comic books smell good. - There's a certain paper smell.
Hold on. This is a series I haven't read before.
(Hold on. This is a series I haven't read before.)
So there are new ones released from time to time.
How was it drawn so neatly?
(How was it drawn so neatly?)
So the artwork is displayed like that.
Oh, yes.
(He reads the book of his idol on the street he dreamed of.)
(He focuses on it without caring about the time.)
(On the busy street,)
(he has fallen into the world of Ito Junji.)
Excuse me.
What? Who is it?
(A man with yellow hair approaches Kian84.)
- It's Kangnam. - It's Kangnam.
It will be great if he can help with speaking in Japanese.
- Right. - Right.
Did Kangnam make all of this happen?
I thought Kangnam was popular in Japan.
- But nobody knew about him. - Right.
Nobody knew about him, but he just went to his office...
and held a meeting.
- Kangnam? - Really?
Also, Ito Junji is known...
- for not being that active. - Right.
He's someone who is hard to invite even in Japan.
You have to feel really grateful for what Kangnam did.
- I was with him. - Right.
He didn't sleep until 4am to make this happen.
Really?
- Kangnam? - I feel so grateful.
Kangnam put everything together.
- Right. - I should treat him well.
- Let's get going now. - Right.
Let's go.
You've got a lot of things prepared.
I prepared a few things.
- I bought a few comics. - Aren't these Ito Junji's works?
- Right. - Aren't these Ito Junji's works?
I did some drawing to give him a gift.
(I did some drawing to give him a gift.)
That's amazing.
Let's go.
- Didn't you buy these? - What?
- You bought the books, right? - I did.
- It's an art book. - Right.
I wanted to go through it with him.
(Checking)
So we can eat together,
Right. Why do you have so many things?
I made kimchi fried rice in the morning.
We have to drive there.
So he has a car in Japan.
It's his father's car.
Let's go.
(Let's go to meet the writer you've dreamed of.)
It's finally time.
(He finally heads toward his idol.)
When you meet Ito Junji,
what will you say?
I got myself prepared.
Really? Did you practice?
I practiced a lot.
I've practiced the answers...
- to the questions that I prepared. - Right.
But I'm worried about...
trying to talk with him.
- If you translate everything... - That won't work.
- That won't work. - Right.
Since I'm not a translator, I can't translate everything perfectly.
I might not be able to deliver everything you want to say.
Right. He can't do that.
I've done several practice conversations with my tutor.
- Really? - You worked really hard.
After getting to meet him,
it won't seem right for everything to be translated.
- Right. - That's one way to respect him.
Does he still create new works?
I wanted to ask him about that.
- If he is still active? - I'm curious about this as well.
(He gets closer to him as his long-time fan.)
(His lips dry up.)
(Fiddling)
He's starting to feel nervous.
(He seems to feel restless.)
Why do I feel nervous?
This is fascinating.
(He feels more nervous than ever.)
I never thought about being able to meet him.
This is it.
(He feels even more nervous after arriving.)
Gosh.
(The time he waited for is just about to happen.)
There's a meeting room there.
- We should get there first. - Right.
(They move quickly as they don't want to be late.)
(Letting out a sigh)
(Looking around)
Where is it?
Shogakukan.
- Isn't this Jimbocho Station? - Right.
There's a bookstore street.
There are many second-hand bookstores.
(A bookstore street near Jimbocho Station in Tokyo)
It's really big.
- It's huge. - Right.
"Doraemon!"
- "Doraemon" as well? - Many famous works were made here.
- Really? - Yes.
(Publisher of "Doraemon," "Inuyasha," and "Detective Conan")
(Ito Junji's "Uzumaki" and "Gyo" were also published here.)
The great works we know of were all published here?
Right.
(He follows the steps his role model took.)
- It's this one. - Right.
- This is it. - Is this one?
There were a few buildings. This was one of them.
- You must be nervous. - He must have complicated feelings.
It must feel strange to be there.
Gosh, this is fascinating.
(Forced laughter)
Gosh, it's fascinating...
- to be here. - Really?
I've been to many publishers...
- in Korea. - Right.
I got the chance to visit a Japanese publisher.
- Gosh, I feel nervous. - The meeting room.
Hey, I need to pee.
What?
- You must've felt really nervous. - Right. I had to go.
(His bladder goes wild with the extreme nervousness.)
(You're back.)
(He enters the meeting room feeling a lot lighter.)
- Even I'm feeling nervous. - I feel nervous as well.
- Will you sit there? - Yes.
What about Ito Junji?
- He can sit here. - Is that so?
What should we do?
- Should we sit here? - Yes.
Is there a certain culture?
- What kind? - Is there a certain place...
where the guest should sit?
I have no idea. Is there something in Korea?
- No. - No, right?
Should I sit there?
Do you want to sit next to him?
- That would be weird. - Right?
(Let's just sit like this.)
Let's do this.
Hold on.
I wrote some questions.
I see.
- Those are his questions. - It's a rehearsal.
Listen to me.
- It feels like... - What?
It feels like...
a dream to meet you like this.
To meet you like this.
(Stopping)
- Gosh! - Gosh!
To meet you like this.
- To meet you like this. - Gosh, that startled me.
Gosh, that startled me.
That's not him, is it?
- No. - That's not him?
- He's skinny. - Is that so?
Gosh, that startled me.
(My heart is beating so fast.)
Give it a try.
I'm currently on TV shows.
I'm currently on TV shows. That is what I do right now.
That is what I do right now.
- "That is what I do right now." - "That is what I do right now."
(He's working hard for his final moments of practice.)
(Rattling)
Gosh, that startled me.
- What is it? - It's the fan heater.
Why does the fan heater sound so scary?
It turned on like a scene from Ito Junji's works.
It feels like he will come out from there.
- He's all sliced up. - Right.
He's all sliced up when he appears.
My hands are getting sweaty right now.
Should I start from the middle again?
(He gets himself together and starts practicing again.)
(Hesitating)
Gosh, I don't know anymore. My mind is going blank.
How would it be for me if your mind goes blank?
Would it be rude if I'm not able to speak well?
- No. - Never.
- It would be better. - Your hard work would move him.
That sense of nervousness...
- is seen positively. - Right.
You've lost all of your confidence.
Why did I want to meet him?
(He keeps drinking water.)
(He feels nervous as well.)
I feel dizzy. This is bad.
You should help me out when I'm struggling.
Of course. I'll make sure to help you out.
(Letting out a sigh)
Imagine he went there alone without Kangnam.
Gosh, they wouldn't have been able to talk at all.
Since the last time I met you,
I started learning Japanese.
Your Japanese has improved.
Was it around six months since we last met?
I studied for around six months.
(Someone's knocking?)
- He's here. - He's here.
(Is it really him this time?)
Was it around six months since we last met?
I studied for around six months.
(Someone's knocking?)
- He's here. - He's here.
(Is it really him this time?)
Gosh!
(The one person who was my idol for a long time)
(The one person who inspired me all the time)
(My universe...)
(that felt so far away from me)
Out of the writers in Korea,
there won't be many who have met Ito Junji.
- I doubt there will be a lot. - Right.
(Meeting my role model, Ito Junji)
(To meet my universe,)
(this small star has come so far.)
(It's time to live that dream.)
Sir!
- It's a pleasure to meet you. - It's a pleasure to meet you.
Gosh.
Sir!
(His role model has finally appeared before his eyes.)
Hurry! Go and greet him.
- Gosh! - Gosh! It's really him.
- Right. - Gosh!
How would that feel?
It's really him.
(Peeking)
Gosh, it was really fascinating.
Hurry! Go and greet him.
- It's a pleasure to meet you. - It's a pleasure to meet you.
(It's an honor.)
- Gosh. - It is really fascinating.
- You may sit there. - Here? Right.
(Sitting)
Why did you sit down first?
Your rudeness was still there.
(His rudeness is shown even to his role model.)
He's old enough to be my parent,
so I wanted to be polite.
He sat down first.
(Overwhelmed)
(He bows again.)
(He can't even meet his eyes.)
- He became a young boy. - Right.
- It feels like... - Just like that?
It feels like...
a dream to meet you like this.
Thank you.
My goodness.
(Finally Encountering My Dream)
(Finally Encountering Reality)
(Only the sound of typing can be heard in the quiet office.)
(Kang Yong is focused on his work.)
(Peeking)
(Checking)
Right.
I made a reservation for noon.
I'll be back.
- Good luck. - Thank you.
I took the afternoon off...
to find a new house.
I got off work early for that reason.
You're finding a new house?
Are you planning to move?
I'm already looking for my ninth house.
There are several reasons why I'm planning to move.
It takes a long time to get to work...
as I live quite far away from my workplace.
There are times when it takes 2 to 3 hours back and forth.
I live in Jangchung-dong.
It takes an hour and 20 minutes when there's traffic to Sangam.
It's tragic.
I get stuck on the road.
I wanted to reduce the distance for my commute,
and decided to look for a new house.
A commute of 2 to 3 hours back and forth would be very tough.
This is the second reason.
Including my current house,
I've lived only in studio apartments.
The mattress is placed right behind.
The wardrobe is right there.
I take a turn, and the restroom is right there.
Since all areas were packed together,
it dropped my efficiency.
It feels like nothing was cleaned up in a place like that.
- Right. - Right.
I felt like I was regressing,
so I wanted a place with separate areas.
That was why I decided to move.
How many months are left before your contract expires?
I have around two months left.
Two months? You should be quick to look for a place.
(Kang Yong moves quickly.)
Where is he going?
These are the things to ask about.
The lump-sum deposit rental's...
interest rate.
I suppose that's the only thing I have to ask about.
- Hello? - Hello.
- Are you the consultant? - Yes.
- Hello. I have a question. - Right.
I gave you a call because I have questions...
about the lump-sum deposit rental.
Pouring my heart and soul. That's not enough.
Pouring my heart and soul's soul.
I have to pour my heart and soul's soul.
I'm living on a monthly rent right now.
It's a monthly rent of 580 dollars with a 30,000-dollar deposit.
It's a monthly rent of 580 dollars.
I have to use everything possible.
If I were to get this loan...
and that,
I think I can secure up to 200,000 dollars at most.
I am in need of a loan.
Right.
What is the interest rate for a lump-sum deposit rental?
It's around 3.9 percent to 4.2 percent.
- It's high right now. - Right.
So this is lower than a different IBK.
Our interest rates are the same for all of our branches.
- Is that so? - Yes.
At the branch near my place,
- I asked briefly about it... - Yes?
around a week ago.
I was told it was around 4.4 percent.
I think the fixed interest rate was mentioned.
Right.
It's not 4.4 percent.
It should be around 4.5 percent to 4.8 percent.
Is that so?
Have you ever gotten a loan before?
- It's my first time getting a loan. - This is your first loan?
- Really? - I've never gotten one before.
The interest changes each time you ask.
- Right. - Right.
It's like the exchange rate.
Last week's interest rate won't matter anymore.
- Right. - Right.
As for your certificate of employment,
it can be replaced with...
the certificate of health insurance qualification.
Right.
The tax clearance certificate...
- of Class A wages and salaries. - That's too hard.
The withholding tax book for earned income.
You will need the documents...
of 2024 and 2025.
When you go to the counter of a bank,
they will kindly write everything down for you.
- It's better to go. - Right.
Right.
- They print it out for you. - "Get this document here."
They help you out.
The tax clearance certificate...
of Class A wages and salaries.
The withholding tax book for earned income.
- It's really hard. - I wish it were much simpler.
I've never heard of Class A wages and salaries.
- There are so many of them. - Right.
Class A wages and salaries was hard to understand.
Right.
All of these are listed on the website, right?
No. It's not on a website. You must get it from your company.
Well... Oh, I see.
Can you say it one more time?
What was it again?
The tax clearance certificate of Class A wages and salaries.
The tax clearance certificate of various wages and salaries.
It's "Class A wages."
Oh, right.
- Gosh. - Do you have a second job?
- It's really tough at the start. - Right.
Actually,
it's best to go to a bank and get it explained to you.
It was harder to understand...
- on the phone. - Phone calls won't work.
I have a call phobia as well. It was scary.
You're still young. You have a call phobia?
You can have a call phobia even when you make the call?
- Of course. - Really?
- That's the most severe case. - Right.
- I'm sweating. - That's the most severe case.
- Really? - Yes.
- Most severe case? - A call phobia wasn't just about...
- incoming calls? - It's a true phobia when you get...
- scared about a call you make. - Right.
- He has the whole package. - Right.
I didn't expect it to be "Class A."
I thought "various..."
- made more sense. - You thought it was that.
I totally understand.
- That made more sense to me. - It's a hard term.
- That's a hard term. - Right.
I understand why you said that.
It's hard. That term...
- is never used. - Right.
Right. Understood.
- Thank you. - I'll contact you again.
- Right. - Thank you.
(The call ends with various kinds of stress.)
The tax clearance certificate of Class A wages and salaries?
I've never heard of that before.
Certificate of employment.
I applied for the withholding tax book for earned income,
but it didn't get issued right away.
MG Bank? It's right there.
- The bank is in the building? - Right. The MG Bank.
- Right. - That must be convenient.
- Hello. - Hello.
- I was the one who called you. - Right. Hello.
- I'm Ko Kang Yong. - Right.
- This is a bank? - It's fascinating.
It's run under the support...
- of the employees. - It's nice.
Isn't the interest rate for loans good?
Yes. It's around 2 to 3 percent.
- That's great. - Right.
But for an employee loan, you are qualified...
- after working for over two years. - Right.
I'm not qualified for it yet.
That was why I made a reservation beforehand.
(He visits to make a personal loan.)
- Is this all you brought? - Well...
- Hold on. - Right. Take your time.
The receipt for earned income tax withholding.
- Right. - That was needed as well.
But...
I can get that issued...
- after I get my pay for February. - Right.
You can give me the one for 2024.
Really? But I wasn't in MBC in 2024.
- I see. - It was really complicated.
The first page of the year-end tax adjustment result...
- was needed. - Right.
I brought my laptop to show you.
- Must I print it? - Yes.
Send that to me via e-mail.
- Should I do that? - Yes.
(Send that to me via e-mail.)
(Let's see.)
(Peeking)
Why do you keep checking her?
Does this room have Wi-Fi?
- It does. Do you use MBC's Wi-Fi? - He needs a lot of help.
- Yes. I use MBC's Wi-Fi. - Yes. Just log into that one.
Right.
I lost my head during the bank consultation.
Why didn't you ask for her personal hotspot?
(Joking)
I would've if it didn't work.
You could even use a portable Wi-Fi router.
(He manages to log into the Wi-Fi.)
- As a PDF file. - A PDF file?
Yes. Send it via e-mail as a PDF file.
Where's PDF?
- He must be really nervous. - It's up there.
- Via e-mail. - Right.
- That's done. - Right.
Now, you have to fill out this application.
Right.
Actually, I was planning to get...
a lump-sum deposit rental loan.
Right. But as mentioned earlier,
- you haven't worked for two years. - Right.
You aren't qualified for it right now.
This is based on the date I joined my current company, right?
- Right. - Just that date matters, right?
Yes.
(Disappointed)
When you apply for a loan of 20,000 dollars,
you can have an installment plan of up to three years.
It's better for the duration to be longer, right?
- Right. The principal lowers. - The principal lowers.
Right. That is why a three-year plan is usually chosen.
With a 3-year plan for 20,000 dollars,
you will have to pay 550 dollars with the interest rate.
That will be around 600 dollars a month.
- So... - Yes?
- that will be... - From your pay.
- taken out from my pay, right? - Yes.
It will be deducted automatically.
Right.
My pay will look really small.
It feels like paying a monthly rent of 550 dollars.
Right.
But I get that paid back to me in the end, right?
- What are you saying? - That's a loan.
Sorry? But you will be getting a loan.
But I will keep paying 550 dollars.
But you got a loan.
- A loan of 20,000 dollars? - Yes.
(You're right.)
You got a loan.
I studied a lot,
but I got things mixed up.
It's not a savings plan.
Why would you get money back after getting a loan?
Well...
I don't quite remember it right now. But...
- Bring me the beating stick. - Well...
Just stay in the same place. Don't think about moving.
It's my first time doing this.
It's understandable.
- Right. - It's understandable.
- It was new to me. - It's your first time.
So I can get a personal loan...
of 20,000 dollars from the company.
- Thank you. - No problem.
This is so hard.
(This is so hard.)
- Thank you. Bye. - Thank you. Bye.
(Kang Yong got his first-ever loan.)
(Letting out a sigh)
(Feeling heavy)
(Spacing out)
Numbers are so hard to deal with.
Everything is hard at first.
- You feel so drained. - Right.
It's not an area that gets covered...
- by studying. - Right.
- It's about experience. - It's about experience.
Right.
Gosh, I feel hungry.
(He keeps walking while feeling hungry.)
I should ask him first.
Kang Yong.
- Why are you so late? - I just got here.
- What's up? - Pardon?
It's my one-and-only variety show producer colleague...
with whom I joined the company in the same year.
- The same year. - I see.
- Hello? - Hey, Sang Min.
Hey, Kang Yong.
Can you spare some time later?
- The 13th floor. - Right.
Come up to the cafe when I call you.
He was the assistant director of "Where Is My Home."
We joined the company in the same year.
He must know a lot then.
He moved to a place very close to the office last year.
Since he recently found a place,
I thought I could get a few tips based on that.
That was why I decided to spend some time chatting with him.
- Since he has the experience. - Right.
- What's up? - I took my afternoon off today.
And I will look for a new house.
- You're planning to move? - Yes.
You live in Sangam.
- You live right here. - Right.
But as for me...
- You spend more time here anyway. - I... Right.
I live there just to reduce time...
- for my commute. - Right.
- Sangam isn't... - Variety show producers...
usually spend all night working.
It's better for producers to live near the office.
Right. He lives very close.
They have to spend time at the office anyway.
I don't spend much time at home.
- Where are you going? - Well,
I'm going to check out places in Gangseo-gu.
- Right. - There's a reason for this.
I didn't want to live too close to the office.
Right.
I want it to be close, but not too close.
If I wake up and see the office building,
- that would feel a bit... - I can see the office building.
- How does it feel? - It isn't easy.
It's not that pleasant.
Why is that? Isn't it better to be close to the office?
The seniors will call you out.
- You have to live away. - Really?
You have to be at an awkward distance...
- when you are called for. - Right!
- Not too close but not too far. - Then,
what is the most reasonable distance?
In terms of public transportation, it should be a 30-minute ride.
Around 30 minutes?
- Around that much. - Right.
Did you go when the seniors called for you?
- What? - Did you go?
- Me? - Yes.
I usually never got called out.
- There's this. - Really?
Seniors have preferences as well.
I wasn't called out as well.
I lived in Mok-dong, but I was never called out.
- I wasn't called out. - Never.
But Kang Yong is someone who would be called out.
- Surely. - Right.
- There are certain tasks. - Right.
(I will go as well when needed.)
Have you ever done a lump-sum deposit rental?
Yes. I got a lump-sum deposit rental.
Didn't you get scammed?
- Really? - Right.
- What? - The "Where Is My Home" producer...
went through a lump-sum deposit rental scam?
- My goodness. - No way.
- I got a lump-sum deposit rental. - Didn't you get scammed?
- Really? - Right.
- What? - The "Where Is My Home" producer...
went through a lump-sum deposit rental scam?
- My goodness. - No way.
- Oh, my. - It happened before the show.
He's a smart man...
- who has knowledge in the field. - You can still get scammed.
- That's right. - Being smart doesn't help.
- You can't get all the information. - It can't be helped.
- Being smart doesn't help. - I guess there are many scams.
So many.
How did you fall for the lump-sum deposit scam?
It might be that they weren't out to scam you.
If the property price falls...
and the landlord can't return your deposit,
you don't get your money back.
That's right.
That's why you need to get a surety bond.
If you get a surety bond,
- the insurance company pays you. - Yes.
Didn't you get a surety bond back then?
- It was a newly built apartment. - Okay.
You can't get it if there's no officially assessed land price.
Really?
- Then you can't get it. - Gosh, it's hard.
- It is, right? It's really hard. - Yes.
So I should get a surety bond for the lump-sum deposit rental.
Give up on the things you can live without.
That might be the size of the house or...
You're right. I should give up on a few things.
You need to look into it in detail.
When you draw up a contract,
- check the special conditions. - Special conditions.
Check the open-end mortgage.
Check the date you reported a change of address.
Don't trust the realtor too much.
That's right. That's the most important tip.
Why are there so many things to check? Seriously.
- I'm new to this, so... - Thank goodness you met him.
Okay. I need to get going now.
- I need to head down. - Okay.
- I'll get going. - I'll keep in touch.
- Okay. Keep in touch. - Okay.
I need to hurry up.
(Kang Yong moves hurriedly.)
All right.
My goodness.
Is it only 1pm?
It feels like 6pm.
(That's how he feels.)
Let's hit the road. Let's go.
(He drags his tired body outside and hits the road hurriedly.)
(Looking around)
There are so many apartments.
How many units are there?
(He sees a forest of apartments in the distance.)
Now, apartments catch my eyes.
(There are apartments...)
I didn't know that there were so many apartments.
(everywhere he looks.)
But my home isn't there.
That's the reality.
Will I be able to find my place...
among those countless apartments?
There are so many apartments.
There are a lot of them.
(Kang Yong reaches his destination.)
I'm here.
Let's go.
I'll get my ID card just in case.
Okay.
- My goodness. - I got introduced...
to a realtor who gives you information...
in a friendly manner.
- Hello. - Hello.
- I made an inquiry the other day. - Okay.
- About an apartment in Hwagok-dong. - That's right.
- Please sit here. - Okay.
Hello.
(Excited)
(Looking around)
- You fantasize about your place. - Yes. I was so excited.
- Hello. - Hello.
- You want a place near Line Nine. - Yes.
I made an inquiry.
We found a few places in Gangseo-gu...
- and Gonghang-dong... - Okay.
- near Line Nine. - Okay.
I asked the realtor to find me a place...
near Line Nine of the subway...
because I might need to go to Gangnam.
(Line 9 connects Gangseo-gu and Gangnam-gu.)
There's MBC Academy in Jamsil.
They often hire me for a special lecture.
Since the traffic is bad on weekends,
I need to take the subway.
Then express trains are the best.
So I thought Line Nine would be great...
and asked the realtor...
to find me a place near it.
When you cross the river from Sangam,
you reach Gayang and Deungchon.
Those neighborhoods are close to my workplace,
so I picked Gangseo-gu.
Other details I asked for...
were a guaranteed parking spot,
a place for running,
and a coin laundromat...
near the place.
Those were the details I asked for.
He has many demands.
- He's picky. - He's picky.
We picked three properties.
- They're the safest properties... - Okay.
out there.
The first place is in Hwagok-dong.
It's a studio apartment for working and living.
A studio apartment.
The lump-sum deposit was 200,000 dollars,
but the price rose and it's now 210,000 dollars.
- It rose. - The price rose quickly.
Compared to the time of inquiry,
the price rose by 10,000 dollars.
If I collect all the money,
I'll be able to get 200,000 dollars.
The lump-sum deposit for this place is 210,000 dollars,
(The first place is out of his budget.)
If it's just 10,000 dollars short,
- he'll keep thinking about it. - That's right.
I'll need to collect...
all the money there is to get 200,000 dollars.
Would it be possible to pay less lump-sum deposit...
and throw in the partial monthly rent?
You can do that.
Decreasing the deposit by 10,000 dollars....
will add 50 dollars to the monthly rent.
- Is that so? - Yes.
The half lump-sum deposit, half monthly rent system is helpful.
So it's 100,000-dollar deposit and 500-dollar monthly rent.
The second place...
is in a multi-household building...
- in Hwagok-dong. - A multi-household building.
- It's a loft apartment. - Okay.
The third place is in Gonghang-dong.
Since this is a newly built property,
you can pay more lump-sum deposit...
- to decrease the monthly rent. - Okay.
If it's a newly built property, is it possible to get...
a surety bond?
He's smart.
It was a newly built apartment.
(He received good information from his colleague.)
If it's a newly built property, is it possible to get...
(He used it right away to ask a question!)
a surety bond?
I loved how he put a hand on his chin.
(Excellent choice)
I think the realtor will ignore him because of that.
(A different opinion)
Since this is a newly built property,
the officially assessed land price isn't out yet.
So they'll have a preliminary appraisal.
But I can't guarantee that you'll get a surety bond.
You'll have to proceed...
after the appraisal...
- comes out. - So the monthly rent is...
There were so many difficult terms.
Essentially, he can't get a surety bond now.
- That's right. - That's right.
In such cases, I take a memo...
and ask ChatGPT what I didn't understand.
- That's a good tip. - That's right.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- The realtor assistant will help. - I'll help.
- Will he visit the properties? - Yes.
Let's go in my car so that it's more convenient.
- Okay. - Let's do that.
- We'll go ahead. Thank you. - Okay.
That's the most exciting time.
I felt like things would go well once I checked out the places.
(With the dream of finding a property he absolutely loves)
I can't believe I'm in Hwagok-dong.
(Kang Yong heads over to the 1st place in Hwagok-dong.)
It feels a bit like a university town.
Yes. The neighborhood is...
very lively.
It felt like the neighborhood in Gwanak-gu...
- near Seoul National Univ. Station. - I see.
(Similar to the neighborhood near Seoul National University Station)
- The building is right here. - Here?
Yes.
(He parks the car hurriedly with high expectations.)
- Let's go. - Okay.
The first place.
It was the 1st 2-room apartment I had viewed in my life.
(The 1st 2-room apartment he had viewed in his life)
I had only viewed studio apartments.
(He walks over to view his 1st 2-room apartment.)
- It isn't this building, right? - It's the one next to this one.
Is it next to a motel?
- A motel. - Is it next to a motel?
- It's full of love. - I was a bit shocked.
- It's between motels. - It was between a motel...
and a hotel.
I haven't seen a place like that.
(The 1st property is between a motel and a hotel.)
Okay. It's a young neighborhood.
The building I currently live in doesn't have an elevator.
I see.
It has been a while since I came to a place with an elevator.
It has been three years.
- Three years. - Yes.
The current place and the one before that didn't have it.
Even if it's a low-rise building...
Listen. You shouldn't get too excited before a realtor.
You should maintain an air of dissatisfaction.
- Am I making a fuss? - You're smiling excitedly.
(He reflects upon himself.)
- Let's go. - Okay.
(Kang Yong exits the elevator first.)
Which unit is it?
It's right in front of the elevator.
- He's so happy about it. - Why does it matter?
Why does it matter that it's right in front of the elevator?
His facial expression screams, "I can't wait to view the place!"
"Move out of the way! Let me enter!"
I can feel his excitement.
- I was so excited. - He'd gladly live in the elevator.
- He can't wait to enter. - His eyes are on the property.
- He's leading too. - Yes.
I was impatient.
(Why did I do that?)
All right. Please come on in.
(Oh, my!)
Can I leave my shoes on?
- No, the place is cleaned. - I'll take them off.
(He exclaims in 1 second...)
(and enters the 1st property.)
(The living room is small, but clean.)
- The apartment is clean. - It's great.
(The perfect kitchen for a single-person household)
(There are the induction cooktop, washing machine, and fridge.)
Appliances are included.
(The first room is small.)
(The second room is slightly bigger.)
I loved that there were two rooms.
You can use them for different purposes.
Yes. One can be a dressing room...
and the other can be a storage room.
But the price rose and it's now 210,000 dollars.
It rose.
- Yes. - You'll see...
- that it's a two-room apartment. - Right.
This property gets a lot of sunlight.
It does get a lot of sunlight.
This side faces southwest.
- Southwest. - Yes, it faces southwest.
(A southwest-facing property that gets a lot of sunlight)
- This place won't get any mold. - What's that?
- What? - What's that?
- It's a checklist that came... - Books have that.
with the book.
Because you've moved a lot, you check the property thoroughly.
Yes. I checked the basics.
As you can see, there isn't a building...
- that obstructs the view. - Okay.
In the neighborhood...
- The view is nice. - Yes.
The view was unobstructed since it was on the eighth floor.
I like that the property is up high.
(I approve of the lighting and the view.)
(Knocking)
- Nice. - Let's go inside the room.
What's nice?
Do you get any information by knocking on the wall?
- Not only that... - I copied what my dad did.
It just sounded like a fake wall, but he said, "Nice."
Why did you say that it was nice?
I don't know.
(The clear sound...)
(leaves him satisfied.)
- You didn't want there to be noise. - That's right.
I like how the window frames are new.
That's right. This building was built in 2021.
- The door is very new too. - That's right.
My current place...
didn't have these windows, so I put a film on them...
- for privacy. - I see.
I haven't seen such windows in a while.
Why do you keep bringing up the merits of the property?
You seem like the realtor.
- I talked too much. - Circulation must be good.
- Circulation is excellent. - Right.
The lighting and circulation are great.
But you know...
(But you know...)
That's good. Be sharp.
Is it long enough?
I see that it is.
(I see that it is.)
"I see that it is?"
At a glance,
- the room seemed small. - He fell in love.
Some people use this room as a dressing room.
- I see. - Let's check out the other room.
Okay.
- This room could be the bedroom. - It's more spacious.
This room should be the bedroom.
- Yes. - Not bad.
You can do that.
You know,
there isn't a closet.
That's right. There isn't a built-in closet.
- A built-in closet. - A built-in closet is missing.
That's right.
So you'll need to get a closet.
I see. That's something I didn't foresee.
- You just need hangers. - I can put it in the living room.
(It's okay.)
I bet this place won't get moldy.
- Right. Both the circulation... - It won't have that problem.
and lighting are excellent.
Right.
The ceiling and floor are good. The circulation is good.
The noise level is good.
I definitely didn't smell the sewage.
(Going through the checklist thoroughly)
(He takes photos of the first property.)
The living room is a bit small.
This is nice. The view is really nice.
(He records the good and the bad.)
This can be my dressing room.
Since the lump-sum deposit is expensive,
I become more cautious and meticulous.
- That's right. - Of course. It's expensive.
(Glancing over)
So there's an automated parking system.
That's right.
- The automated one is tough. - No!
It's inconvenient.
It puts you at risk of running late.
- That's right. - When you're in a hurry...
It's the main contributor for running late.
(Thinking)
(A bit disappointed)
(They return to the car after checking out the first place.)
It's exhausting to view properties.
(They hurriedly head over to the next property.)
The next property you'll visit...
- is still occupied. - Okay.
We got permission from the current residents,
- so you can view it at ease. - Okay.
(Curious)
Hwagok Station. Hwagok-one-dong.
(They go to the next property that's still occupied.)
What kind of a parking lot does this place have?
I see. You enter that way.
The parking lot is in the middle of the road.
- How fascinating. - Is it under the road?
The parking lot entrance is...
- in the middle of the road. - How strange.
This neighborhood doesn't have a lot of parking space.
That's why it's under the road.
If the property is good, I can give up on the parking space.
My colleague told me that I couldn't have it all.
- Some things have to go. - That's what the realtor says.
There aren't many properties that fit the description.
- You're right. - Yes.
The weather is so nice.
Is the weather nice as well?
He says everything is nice.
Could it be that white building?
- That's right. - The white building?
- Yes. - It's nice.
- It was built in 2024. - He says it's nice.
- It's pretty on the outside. - Yes.
- What's this place? - It's nice.
It's pretty indeed.
- Isn't it like a resort? - Yes.
- I like this place. - Nice.
It's a newly built property.
Let's go inside.
- Since it's occupied, - Okay.
- we'll knock. - My goodness.
This place doesn't have an elevator.
Get some exercise.
- On which floor was the place? - Third floor.
- Then it's okay. - You get used to it in no time.
- That's right. - Third floor is fine.
Excuse me.
Hello.
- Please go in. - Hello.
Let's go inside.
Excuse me.
(Oh, my! Gosh!)
(My goodness!)
(The clean kitchen makes you exclaim.)
- My goodness. - It was so nicely decorated.
The terrace is spacious.
The first floor is 13m², but the terrace is 6.5m².
The lump-sum deposit is 55,000 dollars...
and the monthly rent is 780 dollars.
- Okay. - The maintenance fee is 90 dollars.
It looks really different from the photos.
Of course. You have to check out the properties in person.
- My goodness. - There's a terrace.
(My goodness)
- May I enter the terrace? - Of course.
This is totally unexpected.
- My goodness. - Look around the place at ease.
You're saying "My goodness" so many times.
It was my first time at a place like that, so I was fascinated.
How should I use this place?
I can't fill it with sand like Dae Ho.
I guess you could grill meat here.
- Of course. - Why do we always grill meat?
- Every time we see a terrace... - Every time we see a terrace...
This side faces east.
- The view is nice. - Yes.
There are no tall buildings.
All of them are low-rise buildings.
- It's so nice. - Yes. The lighting is nice.
You can rest in the living room.
Seriously. My goodness.
The window isn't very big, but...
It's nice. It's very nice.
- The terrace is nice. - "It's very nice" is too much.
I couldn't hide my happiness.
- May I go upstairs? - Yes. Let's go upstairs.
It's spacious upstairs.
(My goodness! Gosh!)
(Oh, my!)
You could sit here easily.
(There's enough space to sit down.)
That's the bed.
- That's the mattress. - Yes.
(Looking around)
But this place doesn't have much storage space.
- No, it doesn't. - It doesn't.
That's right. So you'll need to set up...
necessary furniture.
- You're right. - Yes.
Okay.
- I lived in a loft apartment once. - Okay.
I don't recommend it.
Really?
It's hard to clean the second floor...
- because you need to be hunched. - The ceiling is low.
Cleaning becomes a problem.
It really hurts your back.
(A realistic piece of advice from someone with experience)
- I'm done with the second floor. - Okay. Let's go downstairs.
There is storage space...
- under the staircase. - Yes. They have...
this storage space.
(He finds a hidden closet.)
So this is the closet.
How will my clothes fit here?
(I don't know what to do.)
There isn't much storage space.
I have many clothes.
- It's a problem. - It's a good experience.
It's a good experience indeed.
(I'll need to head over to the next property.)
Okay.
- Shall we go to the next one? - Yes. Let's go.
I'm curious.
Now...
This property must be the main one they've prepared.
I can't wait to show you the third property.
That's right.
Now, I see that they've saved up the third property.
That's how it is.
They usually save the best one for the last one.
That's right. They plan the tour that way...
- unless it's very close. - They always do that.
The property we'll see next...
comes with a washing machine that doubles as a dryer.
- This is the property. - Yes.
It has an air conditioning system.
It also has a terrace.
- Does it have a terrace as well? - Yes.
That sounds nice.
The road is nice.
The gas station is near.
It's nice to have a gas station nearby.
You'll see the property as soon as you enter.
I feel like...
this property is waiting for me.
- I think it'll be nice. - This is it.
It looks nice on the outside.
- It's clean. - Seriously.
- It was built this year. - This year?
Let's go inside.
Marble. It's nice.
(My goodness!)
- It smells new. - It smells brand new.
Gosh, the elevator opens.
Let's go inside.
Why are you becoming a fool?
Of course, the elevator opens.
Did you think that you had to open it manually?
I was too excited.
"The elevator opens?"
Did it open although you didn't press the button?
I didn't see him press the button.
(Gosh, the doors open on their own!)
I think this property will be nice.
Yes. You'll be satisfied with the condition.
I think it'll be very nice.
Hey, the look in your eyes changed.
- You fell in love. - I was too excited.
- Let's go inside. - Okay.
(His heart beats fast.)
This property is much bigger.
(He finally enters the third property.)
(My goodness)
(It's full of the new-house smell as Kang Yong wanted.)
- This is it. - This is it.
The new property is nice.
This one is the best.
The deposit is 105,000 dollars and the rent is 550 dollars.
(His eyes go wide.)
This washing machine doubles as a dryer.
Everything is nice.
There is enough storage space.
(Opening)
The film is intact because it's a new property.
(It's so nice.)
(Oh, my!)
Why is the terrace so big?
This is the place with a 19m² terrace.
(There's a terrace as well.)
- This side faces north. - Okay.
It doesn't face south.
You're right. It doesn't face south.
It faces north. I haven't lived in a north-facing apartment.
Although it faces north,
it isn't towered over by other buildings.
So you'll get some sunlight in daytime.
- Let's check out the interior. - Okay.
Is this the boiler room? A restroom?
- It's a restroom. - The door is very small.
The door is unusual.
The door is a bit small.
(Unsure)
The restroom is a bit cramped.
- It's cramped. - Yes.
The restroom is very cramped.
(It's a bit small.)
It's a bit small.
If I take a shower like this...
(All right.)
Do I need to use it like this?
It's too cramped.
(I wish the restroom weren't so small.)
This is a 1.5-room apartment,
so there's a room further inside.
Once there's a bed inside,
it'll be like this.
So my bed will go here.
Where will I store my clothes?
- This place doesn't have a closet. - You're right.
That's why a 1.5-room apartment can be a bit difficult.
I see.
These days, 1.5-room apartments don't have much storage space.
- This property is the same. - There's no built-in closet.
That's right. It's a bit small.
(Still, I'll record everything.)
Still...
(He takes photos this time as well.)
There won't be much noise.
Circulation. Circulation is good.
The water pressure is good.
Not much storage space.
(He makes a memo of the shortcomings.)
There are some things I'll have to endure.
(This isn't easy.)
It isn't easy to find a place.
I've lived only in properties with monthly rent in the past.
The lump-sum deposit wasn't very big.
In university towns, it was as cheap as 5,000 dollars.
At most, it was 10,000 dollars.
Nowadays,
the amount of money that goes into finding a place...
has another zero.
I might have to borrow some money from my parents too.
The level of responsibility is different.
My anxiety level was on another level.
While I'm trying not to have too many expectations,
this is a house I'll live in for the next two years at the least.
I'll visit more properties on the weekends...
to find a place I can be satisfied with.
It must've been hard to view all the properties.
- Please keep in touch. - Thank you.
I thought I'd get hooked on the last place.
It's too bad.
Viewing properties isn't an easy task.
(This Is How You Become An Adult)
(Next week)
(He has eagerly waited...)
(to meet his role model.)
(Mr. Ito Junji!)
(Moved)
(He finally faced his idol of many years.)
(I couldn't close my mouth.)
(I...)
(The appearance of his idol...)
(scrambles his brain.)
(Anxious)
(I wanted to pee.)
(I saw your drawing.)
(It was cute.)
(Did Ito Junji see my drawing?)
(What an honor)
(And...)
(he prepared something for him.)
(Kian84's....)
(packed meal with Ito Junji's vibe)
(I'll enjoy the food.)
(How does it taste?)
Hold on. I can't watch this.
(And...)
(I became...)
(a bit emotional then.)
(Ito Junji felt his sincerity.)
(Why couldn't I become...)
(a great cartoonist like him?)
(The Man Who Makes Me Dream)
(The man who doesn't allow a speck of dust,)
(Bae Na Ra)
(He's committed to his routine.)
(He leads a neat life. He seems like a nice man.)
(Seeing Bae Na Ra's neatness and calmness puts me at ease.)
(He fills each day with his unique rhythm.)
(As long as I have a sleep mask and ear plugs,)
(I can go anywhere.)
It's hot.
(It has been a week since my last performance ended.)
(For his hard work, he gave himself...)
(a camping day.)
(Peeking)
(He can enjoy solitude...)
(at his secret spot on the beach.)
(He has enjoyed camping for 4 years.)
(Na Ra's another house)
(Each item has its place.)
(His second sweet home)
(Thorough)
(He has his unique know-how...)
(for maintaining his routine.)
(Eating well is essential.)
(He takes care of himself with each and every meal.)
(Salivating)
(Na Ra's meal)
(This is how a man with a routine enjoys camping.)
(Does he have a running routine?)
(The webfoot octopus run is all the rage these days.)
(Webfoot octopus, I'm on my way!)
(10 minutes before meeting you)
(But he goes further into the mountains!)
(Gosh, I'm exhausted.)
(Na Ra will collapse before he gets webfoot octopus.)
(- They aren't in season yet. - You don't sell them?)
(The webfoot octopus run loses its purpose.)
(Webfoot octopus, this has to be a lie.)
(He feels empty as if there's a hole in his heart.)
(Na Ra Camping With Ups And Downs)